all right hello I'm dressed as a unicorn
although there we go
can't see the the horror at the moment
Happy Easter
it's a most Easter e1z that I have so
decide to wear it today I also got my
hair cut yesterday on Zoom with my
hairdresser which was pretty pretty
interesting we hadn't tried three
different streaming services because
Facebook was too small we had to do it
my hallway because if I plug it in my
bathroom didn't work I could barely see
sweet ride straight hard without the
camera that's what I'm on right now and
it's a camera like right here it's on
the wrong side I always want to flip it
the other way but anyway then we went on
zoom and it worked that bite and she
walked me through how to shave my sides
of my head and my kid helped and so I
currently have freshest haircut now so I
wear my glasses because I needed to put
them on and I felt sick my contacts you
don't it's the wrong thing know what the
wrong thing good I'm definitely pretty
open to most things if they're not truly
even then sometimes hopeful of its own
eyes they could go off a tag attach it
but someday for now I'm gonna try Sunday
is being story time and so well I was
sitting in almost meditation because my
kid is on chocolate and kept coming to
number tea five seconds to tell me
exhausted as is our life now I decided
to talk about my neurodiversity my brain
journey because it has been through a
lot if someone that still wants to call
in they can follow the link in the
description on YouTube especially if you
have a narrow diversity story brain
change a experience where you found out
your you thought differently acted
differently than other people and what
that away cane was like so as every
story that I start it was born on a cold
January morning
I'm pretty periscope I can't
neuroplasticity like the way our brains
stay the same I will after is there a
way I can do one on periscope sorry I am
streaming on periscope I don't know what
you're saying do you mean to join in
from periscope
unfortunately periscope doesn't really
let you like I could comment but you
can't follow the link so it's not very
helpful
XO I'm gonna do that today but this
links aren't that long so that's it see
if you would like to join in on camera
however if I've yet to meet you you need
to be on camera cuz I won't if I don't
see you image or not gonna let you join
the the broadcast because who knows I've
had some seven questionable auditory
joinings from scope so I can only
imagine if I don't see a human being in
the picture what that is but if I know
you you're totally welcome to come on
voice I know some people it is
well disconcert him to be on video even
if you're not dressed up as a drawing
unicorn yeah right now we have a paid
subscription to it so you can just ring
yards so you can string into different
locations and it's unlimited streaming
so before when I was on the free one it
was like 20 20 hours per month and you
couldn't stream in two different
locations unless you paid for the
subscription so how does one I'm
currently on but today let's focus let's
focus which is hilarious because my
brain doesn't focus and when I want it
to only when I don't want it to like you
know randomly 2:00 in the morning
let's create a new transportation system
live 8:30 in the morning oh all the
thing is he could be thinking about so I
was born in the 80s we it's a funny cos
looking back I didn't know I was
intelligent when I was a child I think
just because children are as curious as
they are and as intelligent as they are
and so things stuck or they didn't stick
I was very interested in our religion as
a child I read through the Bible when I
was in grade 4
I am which i think is fairly unique I
don't think votes for grade fours or
read the Bible I don't know how much I
understood but I did read it from cover
to cover and we it's weird is looking
back like I have three things that make
my brain medically unique to than the
rest of the world I mean I think
everybody is it is neurodiverse I don't
really believe in neurotypicals mainly
because my brain so isn't her own
typical I don't even know what that
would be like I'm sure they do exist but
at the same time how do you know how do
you know what anyone else's brain is
like unless you've been in it and you
haven't you've only been in one I've
been in multiple in my brain because
it's continually changing and that's
what makes it unique so I had a TD my
whole life and I knew that I had a TD
but my brother had it worse than I did
so I didn't feel as a TD as him but I
knew I was definitely fair to everyone
else I think if I hadn't had a TD maybe
I would have been seen as intelligent
and junior in like elementary school
because I wouldn't have associated might
me with like Jubilee cats it still it
needs to get up and talk to her friends
all that talk to everybody in the
classroom and those kind of things where
I don't know there were things that I
didn't there were things that stuck
automatically in things that didn't
stick and looking back I think I was
fairly good at retaining information
especially if I was curious about it but
I didn't know I'm sorry master Merritt
is exactly I created great but again
they exist
neurotypicals again I don't know and so
I've known I was a TD my almost my whole
life once my brother was diagnosed and
it became apparent that most people my
family are my my uncles and me and my
brother my sister are way less so I
don't actually think she's a to date at
all this she just likes saying she was
things she could have overcome them um
but having what a lot of what like life
circumstances masked a lot of my
neurodiversity I didn't know I was
autistic till last year partly because
we moved around so much in my childhood
that I associated not having friends and
having trouble fitting into groups from
that and that could vary like we I went
to I counted them up before this I
didn't count them up on camera I'm in
just seven different elementary schools
which is kindergarten to grade six I
repeated grade three so in eight years I
went to seven different elementary
schools and I lived in eight different
houses and on top of that even though I
went to eight different sorry seven
different schools I did not count up the
teachers that I know in grade 3
specifically I had a teacher I was I was
given and then I was given a new teacher
and we had to go to these little cubicle
or do they called I don't even know that
aren't like in the main school and in
the secondary school which was cool
because I was in grade 3 and it made me
feel grown up and then we moved from
Edmonton Raymond and I had a teacher two
teachers that taught that grade and then
they decided four teachers my first year
of grade three and how they decided I
should repeat grade three yes I don't
know it wasn't fitting in I was having
trouble struggling after having four
teachers and then the second year I had
two new teachers so I mean they taught
together so it's but seven teachers for
two years of grade three which is a lot
I think even more than that I think we
moved yes we moved halfway through my
grade three-year tip for the Edmonton to
Raymond and then we moved halfway
through my second grade three year to
left bridge moving ahead for for schools
for grade three that is a lot well I was
having social trouble like I always felt
like I didn't quite belong and it was
hard to make friends granted Raymond was
an entire what if I called town full of
Mormons and we were Christian so we
really didn't fit in even nobody really
wanted to play but that was beyond like
even there was just Sir circumstances
beyond like Anne in Edmonton we had a
very I don't know like there was like a
gang of children and so everyone fit it
and even if you didn't fit in you didn't
necessarily have a friend but like there
was enough kids outside playing in the
common area you'd always have something
to play with and then so there was
people to play with but I didn't really
have a friend and then we moved to
Raymond and it was like oh
all my only friends really my siblings
was the only ones who gets us and like
our okay with our family and I'm sure
left brain should I had more because of
my imagination I had friend like when I
was younger younger imagination was a
bonus a bonus for four other kids and I
had a hyper imagination
I still haven't shown as I was they
believe in bad the world that works for
everyone
only I could has concentrated on the
writing I wanted to do since I was a kid
then maybe I could communicate it but I
feel like I'm sticking up a childhood
for way too long because there isn't you
like the two-minute introductory part of
the portion but I didn't know I knew I
had a TV I didn't know anything else at
the time and I didn't know it was
intelligent until I got to high school
because in junior high in Alberta
I don't know if it's still the case but
there's elementary to grade six so they
can go to junior high for seven eight
nine and then you have high school for
11 for 10 11 12 and junior High's like
the throwaway years it's like your
hormones kick in don't pay attention
you're going through more peer stuff
that you are intellectual and so I had
this alcoholic teacher that was a I
didn't know he's an alcoholic but I met
his son later who also didn't like him
but he thinking back he's smelling
alcohol all the time but it didn't click
that that was his reason and why he had
issues he had issues me probably cuz I
mean vessel I pay attention in class and
my I was not on medication at basically
any point for a because my brother was
fond of medication he got Tourette's and
and so it was like and he even went off
medication at one point in time even
after trying all of them and so I didn't
and because we were I was less than and
I didn't want side effects I did not go
on ATT buds uh-huh he anyway so high
school this teacher that was both my
math and science teacher told me I was
an idiot literally he was like you're
not smart enough to do mainstream math
and like there's a nicer way to say that
he's like so you need to do money do
math there's no way you can handle it
you should also probably do a remedial
science but we'll leave that up to you
there was like the sciences were split
up into chemistry physics and biology or
you could take remedial science and I
wanted didn't understand anyway so I
went into remedial math
and started off reading your thing don't
you see good c180 oh yeah I know he was
the worst teacher definitely the worst
teacher again I bet his son won at one
point when I was in high school and we
were at a party but horrible but if he
would hadn't been in my path I wouldn't
have went into remedial math and if I
hadn't went into media laughs I don't
think I ever would have known how
intelligent I was because the first exam
that I did I never quite got a hundred
percent because I always made one or two
errors that were kind of like stupid but
I got 99% on almost every math test that
I did in math 13 some like 10 20 30 and
then 13 23 33 so I ended up going I did
for math classes in the three years
because I did I switched in the I
switched I did thirteen twenty three
twenty thirty and I got nearly 99% in
all of them and if I hadn't if I hadn't
written or maybe go math I wouldn't have
gotten nearly a hundred percent I
wouldn't have known I was smart and I
wouldn't have gotten straight A's in all
of my classes I got eighty was an A and
I think I got 277 in German 20 and
everything else I got I got an A in
which is how I got into University four
years later after going to volunteer in
Costa Rica and going to Australia and so
once I get high school I know I was in
television because I've got grades and
that is how you know you're intelligent
it's about getting good grades and then
I went to university I took 4 years off
from between High School University
which is its own story and then god I
knew I wanted to take I wanted to be
marine biologist so I wanted to got into
UBC while I was in Australia I applied
to this program called science 1 which
is at UBC and it's an integrated science
program with like the top science
students people who end up going in
there so they're all the people who
didn't even just get a tease they got
like 99% in school got the scholarships
and it was like 50 of us in class five
days a week
besides our clubs that we did with other
science students and so our physics
professor or math professor chemistry
professor my professor were all in the
same room and although we had individual
classes it was more about
how do we integrate them how to science
apply to chemistry apply to biology you
play math the one downfall that was that
they taught calculus in this weird way
where like some of us didn't have
calculus in high school or mine offered
it but I didn't know what it was so I
didn't take it
and so they taught it in this weird way
where it was like above the heads of
people like me that hadn't taken it
before and way below there's like people
who was a repetition for it was like
this in-between it was just bad so
calculus isn't my strong point and I
didn't do great on it and I really
didn't do great in science one I got
like 60% because I failed physics
because physics wasn't high school
physics where I basically got to go in
the night before the test cram and asic
because it was just following the
equations and putting in the numbers and
doing math it was how do you derive the
equations how does this actually make
sense in science and I thought was not I
was not this physicist and then the math
was difficult between those two but we
did a lot of open book tests a lot of
group tests a lot of so and I was really
good at the biology portion I was okay
at the chemistry portion and I had a 40
other like 49 other peer support people
to help because it wasn't it wasn't a
competitive system even though these
people who went through the like science
is fairly competitive it was like who's
smarter but not if you get an A I'm not
gonna get an A and so universe was
really interesting because I had the
science one experiment and then everyone
else you go to year one and tarde but
then you go to gear 2 and it's a step up
and for us it was like science one was
everyone was in kindergarten but we I
don't know like we did more advanced
stuff so we then when we went into grade
grade 2 we wanted to get her to everyone
else it was a step up and for us it was
honestly a step down and so I took one
grade three three three your three class
that I really loved it won't be route
memorization
when Chavez never really great at I
would cuz this is part of like a TD from
what I understand now is you can cram
information in your brain with
adrenaline and it doesn't stay around
long but that's kind of how you can pass
tests and I it's been really little on
tests with the adrenaline sitting down
ready to test and cramming it in with
with adreno
and there was something about that that
I was like I can pretty much do any test
write an essay over a two-week period no
write an essay in two hours yes and so
University was just weird because it's
also like all of the bell curve all of
like the 80 plus students who get in and
then they redistribute themselves so I
knew and I was a mature student was four
years older than everybody else so I
kind of knew that one put a lot of these
kids who go to school it's their first
time away from their parents ain't it
partying and I'm sliding down the scale
but I had this hypothesis that I bet you
there were a ton of C and D students
from high school who didn't apply
themselves and were bored and probably
would have thrived in a university and
so it was weird that you needed this
higher grades to get in and all of this
extracurricular but then you
redistributed yourselves anyway it was
like this seems arbitrary than like
medical school UBC's science day one
they asked everyone who plans to go to
medical school and 99% of people put up
their hands because it's not the
engineering students so engineers the
other thing that scientists go into to
go but they go into university to do for
science and at the end of course not
everyone gets into Medical School not
everyone even follows that path it's
just the thing you do if you know
science enough comin up der and I never
wanted to be a doctor one to a marine
biologist and I wanted to did you get
all of elephants and anyway this about
my brain so in year three that's correct
right
I would've been in your floor no I was
in year three and I was doing integrated
science degree so I was taking a college
in genetics and with a minor in
economics but you can't do a minor in
economics with an integrated science
degree so I just took the courses in any
way at a lot of genetics a lot of
ecology a lot of biology I threw out the
biology courses I didn't want to take I
didn't want to take Anatomy I didn't
want to take I wanted to take more
economic students learned that I spent
this entire semester it's been the
second the FIR the last part of the
first semester and into the second
semester with double vision and I
finally cuz I was also working in a in a
laboratory at the time which I got
through science one and I had a couple
other people from science one in the
laboratory we were undergrads we were
paid to be a which was our own record
remember you're paid to do like an
internship a paid during University and
it was an amazing experience because we
were treated like peers in this
laboratory as we were able to like
discuss math with mathematicians because
I was in a math biology lab and although
I didn't understand math as well as
other people I could participate in the
in the lab meetings and so anyway and
here three I had double vision I'm ever
spending an entire like months going
like this I could see like the farm
vision in China right he could write
things down because I couldn't see with
two eyes and I googled my symptoms in on
the laboratory computer I was like I'm
gonna need to take some time off because
this says I am brain tumors I need to go
to my doctor and I went to my doctor and
I remember coming back to the lab and
laughing because I was like well it was
deadly but it wasn't brain tumors it was
dehydration if you know I couldn't last
long time so I spent a couple of weeks
having I guess I don't really need to
take them tell my brain tumor story this
segue I'm gonna go to a telephone at
work I'm going to so I spent two weeks
drinking Gatorade it did not help with
anything I don't think so I ended up
going to the emergency room at one point
in time because I was still double
vision after - after two weeks of
drinking Gatorade and the doctor that
was there took it seriously gave me a
vision test said yes this is worrisome
let's get you in for an MRI but if you
get nauseous in the meantime you need to
come in and I got food poisoning a
couple days later I knew this would
poisoning but I'm salsa leg he said if I
got nauseous and I went to the UVC met
emergency department basically told them
they have to give me a cat scan and they
were like well you're ripping off the
system but because we're a teaching
hospital and we're slow we all do that
as a favor like you're and then they
came back and they were like so how is
your hearing because when just when you
have a brain scan or really any scan of
your body and they come back to you with
questions about symptoms you didn't know
you had not a great sign so it turns out
I had a three three centimeter acoustic
neuroma in my brain my hearing on one
side was 30% compared to hearing no
other side which again I should have
known because I would talk to someone on
the phone and be like yeah and then be
like why don't you get quiet I
understand and I didn't know that it was
one year they got in to get surgery
fairly fast they had to mount my brain
they had to get that stuff down and it's
not a deadly tumor it's not it's not
generally cancerous it was a really hard
time for my family it was a hard time
but it was also a really beautiful
rewarding time I was saying yes to
things like going to parties and going
to events with friends like I never
really did before I was like alright who
knows I'm gonna die during this I need
to have as much as possible and my whole
family came down for the surgery and I
had the surgery which resulted in me
because my brain corrected for vision as
long as it could and then it couldn't
eat anymore and it went into double
vision when I got it my tumor taken out
and we crossed the other way and I had
extreme double vision that my brain
would eventually coordinate I had I was
deaf in one ear and they severed the
year because they couldn't they couldn't
save the hearing and if I had three
tumors not just one all wrapped around
in in one and but the main thing was
after I mean getting acclimatized to
single-sided deafness is difficult
because you don't know direction of
sounds and you don't know there's a lot
of information you can no longer process
remember walking down the street and
there's a lot of humor like I'm over
here like that's not gonna be helpful in
any way but I was walking down the
street and I heard a baby cry and I oh
there's all these hot cars parked along
here like harass that baby in the car of
like oh it's the person walking this way
with the baby in the baby carriage like
it wasn't it's like everything came from
from my left side because that's the
only sign I hear on but right after my
surgery I was living with my roommate
who if you follow me for long is the one
that made the necklace that fell off of
me in on his birthday this last year in
October and that was just a complicated
and of itself he was a little he had a
crush on me be kind of dated for a few
weeks even though like we've been
friends for years and it was just a bad
time to have someone who has a crush on
you as your roommate because he was
really my brain was swelling and he what
I was thrown
tenter tantrums because he was being too
loud and he was responding to it like
like kind of like an ex who he's a
little boy he's like he's like wasn't
accommodating me but he also wasn't
letting my friends come see me it was
weird like it was like like change to
rest and I did need to rest but
eventually my friends from from school
and from the lab ended up coming in and
demanding I go to the unit to UM to the
hospital to see what was wrong I walked
into my doctor's office the same doctor
described a diagnosed me with
dehydration and I my roommate called
ahead we're like she I can't sit in the
waiting room because I'm so lights
really disturbed me any kind of sound
any kind of smells I should have disturb
me quite yet it was more lights and and
sounds and I went so she put me in one
of the waiting night waiting rooms one
of the exam rooms and I puked in the
sink and I needed the lights off and she
didn't call my neurosurgeon just gave me
a new prescription for painkillers or
something and did he like check if that
was out of the ordinary and anyway so
she sent me home my brain swelled more
and it swelled more it's Walmart so I
would that I had this experience of
feeling like two-year-olds with a bit of
more common cognition than a
two-year-old we're like every sighting
sound I would like throw a temper
tantrum I could like understand I didn't
want you to do this thing but I couldn't
communicate it to you and then my
friends came in save my life or didn't
like gave me a bath because I was I've
had a bath in a few days and then we
went to the emergency room they did a
spinal tap and they didn't know and I
know if it being back in hospital for
for a few about another week and the
first time after brain surgery I was
only in for a couple days so as much and
then I ended up going to stay with one
of mine with my boss from the lab and my
dad would come and watch me and I had to
not like learn how to ReWalk it wasn't
quite that dramatic but Laurie learned
balance and it was harder and I had to
just allow my brain to have this resting
time and what's the point of that okay
besides just bring tubers and fun um
that that
I yeah oh the reason that my brain
swelled was because they took me out
steroids that was that because it's
their policy that's best steroids are
considered a more dangerous drug they
want to watch you while you're on them
and so they took me off of them for my
surgery and might have brain swelled
because it couldn't handle it it didn't
taper it off and so then which I don't
know that'll be important or in this
story because depends on whether taking
gray trade right now I love it to murder
once it's daata eak let's do double
vision which now like it's funny my
doctor I've had so many doctors like
does this and that's something you're
supposed to get in your annual exam
basically every year because if your
sound isn't the same on both sides then
it can be a symptom of an acoustic
neuroma which are quite common well the
brain tumors they're not common but out
of brain tumors they're fairly common
and so I went back did my last year of
university but I really wasn't quite the
same it wasn't as easy if I hadn't been
in fourth year and they kind of made
accommodations like well I was going
through my brain store they definitely
made accommodations I was allowed to
basically do the work I wanted to do and
not do any of the other work but then I
had a whole year to do I had another
year to do so I did that year and I
passed it and I got my university degree
and I went on to you finance a finance
degree as well so I could still use my
brain it was still alright but it wasn't
quite the same and I was always I ended
up calling in sick a lot to every job I
had after that because I was exhausted a
lot of the time from from the
single-sided deafness without really
quite realizing that until my new I was
single-sided deaf I didn't really
realize that the amount of processing
that like the only other time I could
experience not much fatigue in that
matter it was when I was in Germany
trying to learn another language or
you're just so exhausted by the end of
the day sir paintings like trying to
pick up something that I can't quite
pick up and that's what I felt after
becoming definite one year so then five
years later because that was in 2005
that I had my brain surgery in 2010 what
happened why would they Oh cuz I got
nearly MRI scans I got here the other
eye scans and it turns out that the
tumor that oh this is why by the way I'm
telling my story today because I have
the fresh haircut you could actually
when I first get my back of my head
shape actually
my original scar from that one which I'm
a little proud of this has been when
I've been through I have another one
which I've never seen because I've never
had my hair cut short but it's closed
across here um that I got they said it
had grown back and so I either had a
choice I could get surgery again it
would mean I basically have to get
surgery every five to ten years or I
could get radiation on it and so I opted
for radiation even though I really
didn't want to have radiation on my
brain I didn't have radiation anywhere
especially on my brain but it was the
only option so basically so I went in
and got that done for the month at like
December 2010 and my brain has never
been the same since between the swelling
after the first surgery and the
radiation I will I was undergoing
radiation I started becoming really
sensitive to smells I had to take the
public transit even though I lived
fairly close to the hospital it was like
maybe a five minute bus ride and only
one bus bus I like the smells of people
would I was radiation makes you nauseous
and I was I although I didn't puke very
much because I have a suppression of
like a pregnancy and radiation I did and
I went off of pot in order to do
radiation but hurt my koala gist was
like so you show people start smoking
pot not going off of it just you know I
wasn't allowed to take any antioxidants
a guy wasn't always been able to eat
pomegranates and stuff because that
defeats the purpose of it
and I thought I could work while I was
doing it but no you cannot work what
you're doing and it's just you have to
go in every day to get this radiation
and it makes you tired and it's supposed
to whatever you experienced your own
radiation it's supposed to kind of go
away within a few months and my never
did my not radiate my sensitivity to
light increased almost to the point it
was first post first surgery and my
sensitivity to smell but I was still
working full-time and I then had my my
daughter and if I've told this story
before I had three days of labor I it
what forth sorry I four days later three
of which I consider one of which I had
never done all four so it was just 24
hours of lost time really before days of
labor and inna CSEC
and I came home and I'd never had more
energy no new Memphis as that like if
you don't do well ever to this point has
ever said yes this is the most where
it's because I didn't have the
extrasensory stuff because I didn't have
the extra smells and all of this other
stuff uncle babies do couple of smells
uh-huh I it's like my nervous system
calmed down and I was actually someone
came time to go back to work and I'm
like like him go back to what I was
doing which is basically just working 40
hours over four days and then sleeping
through the other three days I clearly
can't do that they didn't make
accommodations I tried to get on their
disability but they wouldn't let me
because they they would make
accommodation so I never get a
provincial disability and while they did
the preliminary work for the radiation
of my brain sorry well they did the
preliminary work and did scans they
found a fourth tumor at the top of my
head and I like to think of it as the
universe telling me for years at the one
they're like you're not listening you're
not listening some acoustic room is all
about your hearing it's on your hearing
nerve and then I went deaf in one ear
and then my life improved a bit because
of the brain tumors and connecting with
people and it was a wake-up call in a
lot of other ways and then I realized
that this is like if you know chakra is
it's like this isn't your connection to
your higher power and it's like right at
my crown chakra it's like right where
the two brain hemispheres meet and right
at the top I was like oh I'm not
listening to a higher power God whatever
that views not listening to my colleague
about less seems like this is going to
keep happening
I finally had that brain surgery to get
that tumor out when my daughter was 2 so
about five years ago so it was 2005
brain surgery for 2010 radiation 2015
brain surgery again and after that brain
surgery I insisted on them giving me
steroids and they were like you don't
know where the doctors it was like okay
cool but this happened last time you're
like well we'll just you don't give
people steroids to take home with them
you have to have it in the hospital and
so the day I was supposed to be
discharged they took me off the steroids
didn't taper them like I took like like
alright and by that day that day at noon
I was nonverbal
I couldn't communicate I was not like I
couldn't move from the bed and they were
like oh turns out maybe you can do
steroids for a while so I ended up
taking steroids taking them home and I
got tapered off over two weeks and I'm
like I'm not seeking steroids here this
is know what's going on I don't want my
brain to swell and anyway so turns out I
know more than they do about my body and
it worked out fine my brain didn't smell
that time but your brain just being cut
open and you're you having to deal with
those things is different why so I knew
I had EDD muffled life my brain changed
from radiation and two brain surgeries
that is honestly very minor brain damage
it's not a car accident it's not I don't
even have headaches I had headaches all
the time as a young kid and then brain
tumors didn't I have these really
intense sharp headaches before when I
was first diagnosed and I think I've
headaches less undergoing radiation but
other than that I don't really get
headaches so every time I get one I'm a
little concerned and you're as well is
this a stroke that's after you've had
radiation it can make those things more
prominent but I know but a radiation -
surgery's minor brain damage and the
amount of impact that has had on my life
has been huge I can't remember I can't
executive function like I used to I
can't I can't
input information like I used to with a
DV where I would cram it in with dren
illan I cuz it all just shuts down I
used to read two or three books a week I
now can read if I really want to read a
book I can read like one a month because
I need a lot of nap time during it and I
can only imagine what it costs to have
more brain damage to have something that
is more traumatic for your brain like a
hit to the head or a something going
into your brain
these were medically induced - like I
said two surgeries by absolute experts
who did an amazing job and a course of
radiation again done by experts you did
an amazing job but my body side effects
from that or like brain swelling after
the first one almost brain swelling up
for the second one and definitely some
brain changes during the radiation which
supposedly doesn't happen it supposedly
doesn't stick around but I can tell you
my brain hasn't been the same since then
and then last year so because I know I'm
a DD and I have brain damage I went to
my doctor
two or three years ago to get a TD meds
so that I could write the book on the
world saving idea that I had let's see
if I can make my brain concentrate for a
day but I know from experience that
having the ATD meds I can't take them
constantly because they I've chronic
fatigue and you can do whatever all of
the interconnection of all of my
disabilities means that I can't take a
TD meds all today every day and I don't
want to whose of my relationship with
pharmaceuticals and so I went to the
doctor to basically say can I get a TD
meds to take when I need them when I
really need to be article for the day
and she understandably it was like well
no that's from seeking that's not what
we do anyone would be able to knock off
their to-do list if they if they got to
matter all like yes but they're not easy
so that's not the same I can tell you my
brain is slightly more neurotypical when
I take this drug but I can't take it
daily anyway so she ended up I'm
diagnosing me with a DD because I had it
as a child not as an adult I had to get
rediagnosis a DS she put me with a
psychiatrist
well we were waiting for that process
she gave me a quiz to see if I'd a DD
and they weren't the normal questions
they were like similar but not quite the
ones that I'm used to with a DD and it
turns out she'd given me the autism
questionnaire by mistake I'm pretty sure
and I was like oh that's weird
turns out I might have autism and then
but but she no way she didn't want to
acknowledge idatv she doesn't was a good
acknowledged autism I went to the
psychiatrist it's like I just like yes
we can't give you a one-off drug but
after trying them for I was like I can
try it for two weeks and I was so
exhausted by the end but it worked while
I was on it so he basically gave me what
I wanted which was here's a prescription
you have a DD and yes you can take it as
a one-off for a week now that now that
we've tried everything else and he went
through listening to doctors you now can
listen to yourself
it's not through my medical just my
brain change story
so then Katie D autism I read this
Twitter feed by by Mike my K his name's
my koala I believe on him for my koala
my K anyway not the point he had he had
this list of
like you might be autistic if it wasn't
like that but it was like there's so
many people out there reading this right
now who wouldn't even know they're
autistic but you're the science and
every single one of them was me and
every single one of them I was like in
tears near the end because I was just
like and so I definitely my self with
autism because when I went in to try and
get an actual diagnosis by my new doctor
because I fired that one for multiple of
reasons we can do a whole story time on
my experience with doctors and why I
don't maybe have the confidence that
most people doing them um even though I
love the ones that like I mean I love my
neurosurgeons and my oncologist I'm
really happy to have these experts in my
life and at the same time the fact that
you go to be off steroids in fact they
didn't listen to me the second time the
fact that all these things not the time
we're not talking that story time so
second brain surgery radiation doctor
ATD so i diagnosed myself with autism
and then i could look back and see oh my
lack of friends is a child my medians
had absolutely not be sticky or like I
was a very happy child except when I was
sticky and then the world would fall
apart and even now as a 40 rule they'll
be like my dad's thinking I'll put them
in dirt and get them dirty before I'd
let them actually sit there be sticky
I've developed all of the techniques to
not to figure out how to not do that the
floors are sticky it's definitely the
time they get washed because I cannot
have a logical walking on them and I can
look back and see all of them but you go
eco late that's the other thing you
remember what the word is or like repeat
words the other people say where I say
it and there's being genderqueer being
demisexual all these things are
correlated with with autism and so
between those three types of
neurodiversity my EDD I knew my had my
whole life autism which I had my whole
life but I didn't know until I was
almost 40 and then my actual brain
changes that worked night and day it's
not like one day I was this and one day
I was that my brain still constantly
changing from I think again the swelling
and the radiation and the just aging
minimum all of these things getting a
rather large effect on your brain and
then all of the things I have chronic
fatigue fibromyalgia human digestive
orders are all thought to be
neurological and or autoimmune and or
it's like
I wouldn't figure this out because I
strange they don't have the brainpower
and you can't figure out your own stuff
because a placebo effect and all of us
anyway so through this I ended up on
disability at home depressed really for
years
chilling with my anxiety dealing with
what does my life look like now I was
gonna be the Jane Goodall of elephants I
was gonna say world I was gonna do that
by learning everything I could possibly
learn and so I learned genetics and
ecology and I learned economics and I
learned finance and a lot of self-help
stuff in psychology and history and
things that I thought I should know
because people should know them some of
those which I was interested in science
and some math and then some of which I
wasn't quite interesting but thought I
should learn geography in history and
when it came to the point where I
couldn't read anymore I couldn't really
put in new information I knew that I
wasn't gonna become the person who is
who is intellectually a genius oh I
could save the world in whatever weird
abstract way that that was gonna happen
but in sitting in my room in depression
in basically enforced meditation because
like sit your butt down stop doing
anything and just be and I think the
world is going through this right now
with the pandemic of like you didn't
choose this but you're now with it
you're now in your emotion in your space
in your story and from that space it
didn't happen all at once I didn't get
what I have now years later but I write
because I wish I remember the order it
all happened in I just remember being
like oh this is an actual solution this
is something that can save the world
this isn't I've had many fantasy world
in my head growing up and through my
years where it was you know rebellious
teens that took that helps save the
world or this vampire world that I
didn't really play him but I wanted to
like right and I worked out all this
genetics and cool stuff oh this vampire
werewolf world and I can't think of any
of them right now any other ones but
they were like far-fetched like they had
in the teenaged one save the world they
have like a cure for AIDS that like
worked and because that was the time
period that I was a teenager in
and but none of them were real like none
of them were things like that that cure
for AIDS for wouldn't actually work
right
whereas acident and they puts a lot of
like romance involved in it as well and
definitely with males and me figure I'm
queer at 36 is a whole other story
but I mean then one day like the romance
part of it fell away the unrealistic
part of it fell away and somehow in my
30s my imagination became this world
that's actually possible or we look out
for one another and we have technology
that we own together that helps us
create a world that we want without
leaving it up to our governments without
leaving up to outside forces and there
was nothing in that that wasn't fully
plausible there was no time-travel there
was no this is actually possible
us having a technology company we owned
together as a cooperative can save the
world can help us create a world that
works for everyone but now I've got to
figure out how to get it out there with
my neurodiversity with not being able to
learn new skills like Jake I should
really want some public speaking I
should learn how to edit video I should
learn how to do these things so this is
the level that I'm at is like my current
intellectual though I do put new
information in because I can every
conversation I have helps me grow until
I wasn't able to put in external
information in the same at the same
capacity I was only able to rely Cree
mix the information I did have that's
how I created the world that works for
everyone
and so now I'm in those limitations in
my same brain having to communicate it
to the world having to figure out what
does this look like to work for my
position and realizing that our
neurodiverse not just mine
neurodiversity but everybody's
neurodiversity is how we create a world
that works for everyone because our
diversity in our in our in everything
and the way our brain works and where
our bodies work and our similarities and
those same things are how we fuel the
coming necessary revolution that in my
mind is peaceful and
to abundance because it gives us
everything if we all have the exact same
goals and dreams in mind if everybody
wanted to go to Paris at Christmas it
wouldn't work because everyone want to
go to Paris Christmas if everybody
wanted to - if everybody want to do the
same thing we couldn't do it but because
we have a diversity of talents and a
diversity of challenges it's actually
the connection between us that works
there is no task that isn't somebody's
genius and somebody's passion and I mean
literally any task because when I first
started to explain this to people I'm
like like yeah there's tasks that nobody
wants to do like cleaning toilets that's
everybody's first task and the first
person I said that to was like I like
cleaning toilets freaking kidding me how
does that even possible and that that is
kind of the one of the big issues is
that we think everyone is simultaneously
like us and not like us so it's like
because I don't like cleaning bathrooms
nobody likes any bathrooms and that's
not true I don't think we're gonna live
in a world where someone's gonna come
clean your bathroom necessarily for you
but in the public spaces and hospitals
and stuff if there's people want to
clean it awesome and so it's our
uniqueness and the more we let society's
version of our uniqueness fall away
there was a ton of stuff I know and I'm
still sure there's a ton of stuff that I
didn't really like it I thought it was
supposed to like it like and then I
realized how much that's ingrained in me
when I see other people who I think are
authentically enjoying what I don't like
and I'm like but you're faking it right
now I saw kids adults at Ko house that
you know playing physically like playing
hockey playing soccer with their kids I
was like you don't like that hey they're
like yeah no like I'm the one asking to
go and play I'm like oh I don't like
sports and I never I felt like I was in
sports of baking it and I was like I
really don't like that like I I'm glad
other people do that with my kid it's
not my thing it's not and or like going
to cultural events like going to museums
there's some museums I like I don't
really like art museums it's like well I
was supposed to like
I was supposed to pretend to like this
is it supposed to be there's a geek
because I am a geek there was a geek
culture that I was like no I'm actually
not really that like Star Wars not
really that into it like it's not really
a story that speaks to me I kind of
liked it and allowed it to be in my in
my yeah okay cool yeah let's watch Star
Wars again as such because that's what
you did is a geek culture whereas Star
Trek I didn't really like because it was
like my dad's show that I had to watch
because he was watching it and now I'm
watching it is actually yes actually I
like space very learning new things
letting go because if we all think like
golf I think is a great example a lot of
people really do love playing golf it is
it is they enjoy the process of it
however there's a ton of people who play
golf because of the business connection
right because you're business people eat
people want to play it so you go out and
play it that's not you enjoying it so
all those people on the greens paying
greens fees how many those people
actually enjoy being there playing golf
and how many people are there because
everyone else is how many people
watching sports every year truly love
the sport and watch it even if nobody
like if somehow we still have the NHL or
the NFL or the NBA without millions of
people watching right you were the only
one who watched it what would you do if
it wasn't popular what would you do if
it was popular and finding that
combination find you know would I do
this if everyone else was against it
yeah but that's what you want to
concentrate on would I do this if would
I like this just because everybody else
likes it like does that change my my
opinion of it and there's things like
Harry Potter I love clearly it's super
popular I would love it even if it
wasn't popular
I wouldn't necessarily able to talk
about a tour they wouldn't because
culturally appropriate right people
wouldn't know what I was talking about
if I referenced Harry Potter like we
usually do I'd say what a muggle is
right like most people know what that
means but I would still like it because
I enjoy it it's not I didn't force that
on myself
whereas Star Wars I would never ever
watch it unless someone else put it we
might put it on and so what do I seek
out what brings me joy
and although it took me a longer time to
get there with my intellectual pursuits
what do I want to do if it's gonna cost
me to put things in my brain what do I
want to put in my brain and it's not
other people's assignments it's not like
I can't even put in my own assignments
when I want to read a blog post when I
want to read a book it's still hard so
someone else being like just read this
book just do this is never it's like
three people at least have to tell me to
read a book in order for it to click if
you like maybe I should read that book I
think that book is supposed to be in my
life and being open to those because I
don't like my brain changes or something
I am so grateful for because they opened
me up to my own internal wisdom in a way
I never would have done unless I was
forced to I always would have thought
learning more outside knowledge was the
key to becoming who I was supposed to be
instead of the internal knowledge the
sitting with myself the feet led the
learning piece-by-piece who am i what am
i uniquely here to give who are my
people what is my purpose and what do I
need to be able to do that and at every
level I'm able to answer that it pays
for itself it's its own internal drive
and I spend a lot of my life I know now
being a parent no don't know how to do
this for her but yet I'm still tapping
into it a little bit of like the
internal motivation versus external
motivation internal motivations always
gonna be better internal motivation is
now but I have to live my life on and
now what I suggest everyone wants their
life on internal motivation is the key
factor I have a Spoony disability which
means I have to be rather careful about
where I spend my energy I don't have a
limit of spoons as other people with
spinning disabilities but I definitely
have limited spoons and in so doing
because I have limited energy I've had
to figure out how to live my life to the
maximum benefit with the energy I have
so I've had to figure out the
diminishing rate of return on every area
of my life on parenting it is life yes
it is Westborough alive alive every
Marty today
for an hour today we're trying to Sunday
Sunday storytime I mean I have a
conversation set up for Wednesday to
talk about the four questions and what
it is that how we can how we can dive
into them how they actually do help
improve your life because because how do
you like Who am I is a hard question to
answer but there's many ways to answer
it and having those tools in common and
having those ways in common because any
level you answer that pays for itself
and then it's its own internal reward
that's what I was saying in general mr.
Lord
that I have to wait for the motivation
to hit me so I have to wait til I have
the urge to clean my house to clean my
house or I'm like my what I call is my
spoons being on sale it's like when
something's on sale it's 50% off you're
like I'm five of them if I wait till I
have the internal motivation it's a lot
easier to do anything when I push
anything with external motivation like I
want a clean house I really do function
better in a clean house and I push it I
pay for it every single time and so I've
learned that I have to wait from the
internal motivation and that what a gift
that is because when you figure out your
internal motivation there's no external
motivation that counteracts that there
is no opinion by somebody outside of me
it's gonna take my my self identity away
because I know because constantly as
people make opinions I get triggered by
it sometimes and then I'm like where do
I find that piece where do I find that
piece alright my krumping generally not
rub me as it like as right now in this
moment or an individual overall both or
no I'm not grumpy right now and I'm not
grumpy all the time but I do get grumpy
I mean I have chronic pain have
exhaustion anyone happy not get some
gets grumpy but because I have again my
level of patience has had to go up and
up and up especially with my kid whereas
my conditions have gotten worse and
worse and worse
and so to the outside it kind of looks
like a plateau but I know if I ever am
able to get rid of my fatigue and pain
I'm gonna have the patience of a freakin
saint because it's like it's what you
kind of have to develop when you
chronic fatigue and chronic pain you
can't treat everybody horribly all the
time and I don't it's the one I'm in my
lowest place so every day basically
every day I am okay in the morning and
by the evening I'm a friggin witch and
so it's like finding the tools to be
able to mitigate that as a parent to be
able to say okay well I can I'm not
really lunch every day that's that's
pretty pretty extreme and get into
places where I can be bitchy and I know
when to take time to myself and when I'm
overwhelmed and how to not spend my
spoons and I'm still learning constantly
there's still times all the time where I
spend too many spoons and then I crash
for a week or I take too many I just do
too much I take on too much world issues
and then I crash and but if I didn't do
any of that then I wouldn't be where I
am I wouldn't know
feel like I know how we can create a
world that works for everyone I wouldn't
be on here because the reason I'm on
here is because I think I know a way
that works for everyone
and whether or not it's actually the way
that we can create a world it's I
believe it is so if all I can do is go
live and be on Facebook and I'm actually
on Facebook right now I'm on Twitter and
YouTube and all I can do is give my
stories and my path and a version of the
future that we can co-create together
this is all I can do I can't perfect it
I can't do it in a way that yeah it is
on periscope but it says Twitter okay
people don't necessarily is some people
are watching this on Twitter I don't
think I put the link today on Twitter
but generally on Twitter you can follow
the link that was up on the screen fill
up two common participate from camera if
you want but the amounts like society is
not designed for neurodiverse people
there's a lot that I can't participate
in society because of renderer diversity
mainly my brain damage also bit my
autism less so maybe D but even that
like the fact that I show up with a DD
in the world it's not considered a
benefit if you already like oh here she
is really a DD great benefit we look at
it as people who are flighty people who
have less to give people who need
medication to become normal so that they
can contribute to society whereas once I
was able once I'm able this
to how my brain actually is without it
needing to be any different I was able
to tap into my true genius
my actual me not just listen and I did
probably not because you're on periscope
so you pop in and out I don't take
reading assignments from people because
I don't read I can't read anymore so I
only read what I absolutely want to so
if like five people recommend me that
and I know why I should read it than I
might read it but I follow the internal
guidance of what and like society's not
okay with that said he's like like what
do you mean you're not willing to learn
outside information I'm like it's not
that I'm not really it's that I was
given the guidance that that's not
that's not my path it doesn't mean other
people should if you're able to read
books and able to learn things and you
want to learn those things definitely do
it I still learn the things I want to
learn I still watch the videos I want to
learn right now Jen Cove in nineteen I'm
spending way too much time reading about
Cove it 19 when I know I'm not gonna be
able to create a solution for that but
at the same time it's how I deal with
stress is learning its how I dealt with
my owns like my own medical conditions
was learning I did too much of it
because it again placebo effect you
can't actually kind of heal yourself I
need other people's information to be
able to heal myself
doctors need other people's information
you want to kill me because you it's one
person doesn't have enough data but
especially when you're a combination of
traits things when you know what I mean
is this is this thing that I have that I
don't want to have is it because of my
brain damage is it my autism are you DD
that are just part of who I am is it
something that is absolutely just
placebo from my brain and not really
there is it like I don't know and I
can't know unless other people have it
as well is this my result for my brain
surgery is this my chronic fatigue is
this my favor every way oh joy what is
it that actually or is it something
brand new pronouns and so I can't know
that unless there's other people who are
sharing their data for that and so
although that's not word to me right now
like in with together attack it's not
creating the medical app is not creating
the one that we can share data it is
something that we can and should create
together ya know I do listen to
audiobooks which I enjoy and yet I still
have to go to my doctor he got a
prescription for the audiobook so I can
get them for
and I don't know if I fall under those
categories of am i disabled enough two
together which is always the problem
because all of my disabilities are I
acknowledge or not as bad as most of the
people who have those disabilities like
my fibromyalgia is not like I can hug
people I can you know like my body is
that like I said I have a height they
actually might find it might be pretty
bad but I have a iTunes for pain which
is not a common factor in that but I
know I have a high tolerance for pain so
it's a little bit better and easier to
manage than for somebody else but my
chronic fatigue I have limited spoons I
can't just ignore it and know that I'm
gonna wake up with new spoons tomorrow
but I also brushing my teeth and having
a shower doesn't wipe me out for the day
it does wake me on bit so it's like
feeling did somebody like brushing my
teeth can you doing the shower I have a
less often necessarily than daily but
having like other people literally they
get up and they eat they have to go back
to bed because that's all they can do I
have again the guidance from whoever
those guides are whoever is giving me my
genius and my purpose and giving me this
map to follow the guidance is that I get
the energy I'm required to follow that
path that anything I do outside of that
path I'm not gonna have enough energy
for but anything given to me on that
path I will have enough energy for which
is basically like if you had a currency
right or they're like well give you just
enough to pay your bills but if you
spend on anything else you're not gonna
have enough to pay your bills and you'll
get a victim you'll have to go into
bankruptcy but you will get just enough
if you don't spend it on anything for
the list and yet you're a human being
and you still want the only cup of
coffee and you still want an outside
life you know so I still constantly
spend energy on things that are maybe a
little more frivolous but finding path
and that is what I mean I'm still on the
path I didn't like correct my broom
which is what most of the stuff out
there is is I overcame it now I'm better
I don't know if I ever get better and I
don't even think I want to because I
don't even know one what better means
because I'm like this is I've never
given more to society
than I am currently on disability not
leaving my home and although that might
trigger other people it's like I know
that I'm giving at my highest capacity
right now even though in the moment
there might be more I could do overall
there's that more I could do right if I
spent this time reading this book
instead of I don't know watching this TV
show that might be something more I
could do but I would pay for it in
energy later on down the road so overall
when I follow my joy and I followed the
my own internal guide of like yes do
this right now I evolved my project
evolves and everything becomes better
and if I force anything it falls apart
including what I for say when it's not
from someone else I've been especially
when someone outside force is it like
when I am listening to doctors advice
when I know I'm not supposed to
basically the worst it's like alright
get why you're saying to do that but I'm
not falling apart again
I'm just the issue with anytime I
started a new doctor is they're like
well let's put you through all the tech
no not to be the test I know what's here
I know it's gonna say it's not I'll go
for a blood test no problem I'm not
going to a new neurologist and a new
psychiatrist and in do look at my
medical history just look at it I'm not
doing all the tests for you know it's
like when you go to get diagnosed for
gluten you eat it you feel like crap
that's not enough you have to eat it
constantly for three months or some
ridiculous and then go in and get a test
you have to like destroy your body to do
it and there's a lot of things that are
like that it's like well just put your
so I'm like I'm not going to put myself
into stress so you can see that my
nervous system shuts down when it's
under stress I know it I don't need you
to know it and be a doctors need to know
it like that's kind of the issue is I'm
like but which is also a Rika's
doctorate whatever are stressful so I'm
always under stress and I'm with doctors
like you have extreme anxiety you need
to take medication I'm like if I was
like this all of the time I would agree
but this is only when I'm with you this
is my fun medical PTSD torrent Pirate
Bay sure if you give me the link to free
audio books I am down with it I'm on um
you can't really message me on from
Ferris go put him on Twitter at crab
democracy
or my name is Jubilee on YouTube at
Jubilee saves the world by me on train
through life because that is what I'm
doing has this idea in my head that
wants to get out which is getting out
it's yeah India itself has never made me
going to be made into a white pages and
be made available for because it's never
done it's constantly evolving and but
it's my brain is still creating the path
to it it's still like hey let's try it
via cafes how what do we get over to
that what do we try we're trying
solution raising I can show up and have
a conversation I can press go live on a
video so this is what I am doing I am
doing what I am capable of and as other
people join we're capable of different
things that I am we will make it better
and better because it's not about me
putting out something and then it being
the new gospel everything has to be done
in this order it's about everyone living
like their own process their own and as
weird as that sounds it magically comes
together I'm living my life to my
highest standard living listening to my
internal guide looking for other people
who are willing or attempting to do the
same and in so doing I guarantee you
weave together for willing to show up
together we will create a world that
works for everyone
and we are doing it together text doing
that solution raising is doing it you're
doing it by showing up for this this
hour even if you weren't here for the
full hour and now it is past the hour
I'm gonna go hide some eggs in my giant
unicorn outfit so that hit my kid can go
Easter egg hunting I've got some in her
bedroom this morning so it's like
cleaning your room cleaning the room
part didn't help but she did find 15
eggs and get her Easter basket so we
will see how that works but yeah Easter
in the pandemic in isolation he followed
me on he looks around Twitter come on
hey Heather yes
chief what's fine pickup yeah I know and
then I do that right I take on too much
other stuff not mine but I also feel
like it's all mine and not that it's all
mine like I have to do 100% a big sign
no way feel that way it's that mine is
like 5% from each day as opposed to a
hundred percent of one thing and a lot
of people you're one or the other right
you have like one thing that you're
focused on like this is my thing and
that's awesome and there's other people
who are here thank you Shiloh Thank You
Heather and I'm it's been an hour so I'm
gonna get off and I'll see both of you
at some point future this week of
conversations set up for this week I
don't know what the idea of a is gonna
be at this week I don't know the other
thing could be this week
but things are coming together and I'm
looking forward to our four question
conversation on Wednesday Heather and if
either of you want to join for the
solution raising on Wednesday which
there's three topics potential or didn't
I'm gonna work through which one works
all right thank you for hanging out and
I will see you out